A Guide to the William Ingham Papers, 1945-2013: SC 0002
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
William Ingham Papers,
1945-2013
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Ingham, William Herbert, 1947-
SC 0002
37.13 cubic feet; 113 boxes
This collection, consisting of 37.13 cubic feet (113 boxes), contains the professional and academic papers of Dr. William Ingham, professor emeritus of physics at James Madison University.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
William Ingham donated this collection to Special Collections in October 2013.
Other Formats Available
Digitization of media content is in-process as of August 2016. Access will be made available to content once digitization is complete, barring any copyright or use restrictions.
Bio/Historical Note
William Herbert Ingham, a distinguished member of the James Madison University Physics faculty for over three decades, was born November 29, 1947 in Rochester, New York. He received his S.B. (Scientiae Baccalaureus) in Physics from Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) in 1968 and went on to complete his M.S. in astronomy from California Institute of Technology (Caltech) in 1969. Ingham returned to MIT and received his Ph.D. in Astrophysics in 1976. Dr. Ingham began teaching at JMU in September 1976 and remained a member of the Physics faculty until his retirement in July 2010.
During his tenure at JMU, Dr. Ingham served as head of the Physics Department from 1986 to 1989 and also served in an acting role as Associate Dean/Acting Dean, Letters and Sciences (1989-1990) and Assistant Vice President for Academic Affairs (1990-1991). Dr. Ingham's accomplishments related to furthering the science curriculum are numerous. He taught over thirty discrete Physics courses as well as courses in many other disciplines such as chemistry and math and championed a new computational science concentration. He also developed and taught four offerings of an introductory fluid mechanics course beginning the 1980-1980 academic year. In partnership with the History Department, Dr. Ingham was instrumental in creating the history of science curriculum first offered in the 1992-1993 academic year. Related material is located in the Teaching & Coursework series of this collection.
Dr. Ingham advocated for the Physics Department and the liberal studies program during university restructuring in the 1990s. He spoke out against Dr. Carrier and many others in the university administration for decisions made regarding academic restructuring and other tangentially related incidents. On the morning of Friday, January 13, 1995, Dr. Bethany Oberst, vice president for academic affairs announced restructuring plans which included moving math and sciences out of the College of Letters and Sciences and into the College of Integrated Science and Technology (CISAT) and merging the remainder of College of Letters and Sciences programs with the College of Communication and the Arts. Especially shocking to the university community and to Dr. Ingham and his colleagues was the announcement that Physics would be eliminated as a major. Throughout his papers, Dr. Ingham refers to the ensuing months and years at JMU, which included the aforementioned academic restructuring, and also a 1996 Honor Code "fiasco" during which administration quietly overturned an Honor Council decision, opposition by faculty and students to proposed general education curriculum, and quashed subpoenas originally served to Dr. Carrier and civic leader, Zane Showker, as part of the 1997 Jamie Raymond murder trial, as "the troubles." Similar intentionally nebulous language describing these years can be found throughout materials in Series 7 through Series 12. These occurrences, particularly the plans for university restructuring, created conflict between the administration and faculty and resulted in the group, Faculty for Responsible Change (FRC), of which Dr. Ingham was a founding member. The Physics Department ultimately was kept intact and continues to be a thriving department and major at JMU.
Dr. Ingham was also an influential and involved faculty member beyond the Physics Department and beyond JMU. He served on the Faculty Handbook Task Force which was charged with editing the faculty handbook. This included editing and revising the expectations, rights and responsibilities of the faculty, and outlining the relationship between faculty members and the university. He also served on the Faculty Senate. Dr. Ingham was awarded the Distinguished Teaching Award for the College of Sciences and Mathematics for academic year 2002/2003. Recommended by the Council for International Exchange of Students (CIES) for a Lecturing/Research award under the 2004-2005 J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Program. He was awarded a grant and subsequently spent the fall semester 2004 teaching Physics and conducting research at Acadia University in Nova Scotia, Canada as a faculty-in-residence.
Dr. Ingham was professionally active throughout his career, serving as a member of the American Association of Physics Teachers (AAPT), particularly the Chesapeake Section (CSAAPT), and Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society. He was a grader for Advanced Placement (AP) Physics examinations for several years. Between 1994 and 2000, Dr. Ingham served on the AP Physics Development Committee, a six-member national committee that writes the AP Physics examinations; he chaired the committee from 1997 to 2000.
Since retirement in 2010, Dr. Ingham has remained active in the JMU community as a member of the Faculty Emeriti Association and continues to lecture on topics relating to black holes and gravitational waves.
Scope and Content
The William Ingham Papers (1945-2013), consisting of 37.13 cubic feet (113 boxes), contain the professional and academic papers of Dr. William Ingham, professor emeritus of physics at James Madison University. The materials chiefly relate to Dr. Ingham's tenure as a physics professor at JMU between 1976 and 2010, including lecture notes and PowerPoint presentations, homework assignments, syllabi, examinations and keys, and related course documents. Other materials relate to Ingham's scholarly pursuits both related and unrelated to physics including Dr. Ingham's research on James Madison and the sciences. Materials documenting Dr. Ingham's involvement in professional organizations and his commitment to professional development comprise a sizable portion of the collection. Much of the correspondence throughout the collection was generated using the VAX email system.
The second half of the collection, series 7 through 12, includes materials documenting the conflicts and controversial incidents Dr. Ingham encountered with the JMU administration during his time as a professor of physics at JMU. Specifically, these incidents include the controversial decision by JMU administration to restructure academic colleges and dissolve the Physics Department, a 1996 Honor Code "fiasco" during which administration quietly overturned an Honor Council decision, opposition by faculty and students to proposed general education curriculum, and quashed subpoenas originally served to Dr. Carrier and civic leader, Zane Showker, as part of the 1997 Jamie Raymond murder trial. At the request of the donor, the aforementioned series were restricted and closed to researchers until September 18, 2020, three years after the death of Dr. Ronald Carrier.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in thirteen series:
Series 1: Undergraduate and Graduate School Materials, 1965-1976
Series 2: Teaching and Coursework, 1971-2013
Sub-series 2.1: Courses
Sub-series 2.2: General Teaching
Series 3: Research and Scholarship, 1945-2013
Series 4: JMU Departmental and JMU Materials, 1976-2012
Sub-series 4.1: JMU Materials
Sub-series 4.2: Physics Department Materials
Sub-series 4.3: Canadian Faculty Residency
Series 5: Professional Development and Activities, 1958-2011
Series 6: Physics Miscellaneous, 1970-2005
Series 7: Chronological Files, 1986-2013
Series 8: Faculty for Responsible Change, 1993-2008
Sub-series 8.1: Lawsuit Files
Sub-series 8.2: Exhibit Items
Series 9: General Education, 1993-1998
Series 10: Physics Program Review, 1990-1999
Series 11: Reports, 1989-1996
Series 12: Subject Files, 1992-2013
Series 13: Media, 1999-2004
All series and subseries are arranged chronologically with the exception of Series 11: Reports and Series 12: Subject Files, which are arranged alphabetically. Note that within Series 8: Faculty for Responsible Change there are two subseries. Subseries 8.1 is arranged alphabetically and subseries 8.2 is arranged numerically by exhibit number. Series 13: Media is not arranged in any particular order.
Location of Originals
Along with all other media, the USB flash drive is in the process of being digitized (copied) as of August 2016. After digitization, the original drive was returned to the owner.
Separated Material
Due to Federal laws regulating the privacy and use of student academic records (specifically the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, i.e. FERPA), material including but not limited to grades and grade books, marked papers, theses, class rosters, letters of recommendation, and instances of social security numbers or other unique identification numbers have been removed and returned to the donor. Many newspaper articles were photocopied and originals discarded. In some instances where entire newspaper issues were donated, the titles and dates of issues were recorded and originals were returned to donor. All media, regardless of original location in the organizational structure, has been removed to a single series.
- Series 1: Undergraduate and Graduate School Materials, 1965-1976
  Scope and Content
  Arranged numerically by course number and then alphabetically.
  This small series contains coursework and notes completed by William Ingham while he was an undergraduate and graduate student at MIT. Materials primarily comprise course notebooks and handwritten notes.
  - 8.11 "Estimation of Some Broad Guidelines for the Early Development of Astronomy", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 8.311 Electromagnetic Theory, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 8.312 Electromagnetic Theory II, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 8.912 Cosmic Electrodynamics I, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 8.921 Farm/Equipment, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 8.922 Stellar Structure & Evolution II, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 8.971 Term Paper, Radio Sources, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 8.971 High Energy Astrophysics, 8.942 Cosmology, 8.962 General Relativity, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 12.001, 8.17J, & 18.636; A134, A112abc; 12.501, 1967-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ay131, Ay201b, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ay201a, Ay201a Lab, Ay201b Lab, Ay135, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - B.S. Thesis Working Notes (Notebook), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Doctoral General Examinations, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - ERC-Quantum Physics, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ingham PH.D. Thesis Abstract, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Teaching and Coursework, 1960-2013
  Arranged in two subseries. Series 2.1: Courses is arranged alphabetically by course number (beginning with physics) then numerically by course number. Series 2.2: General Teaching is arranged alphabetically.
  This series, comprising the bulk of the collection, contains Dr. Ingham's teaching materials and coursework when he was a professor at James Madison University. Dr. Ingham taught throughout multiple departments. As such, his course material spans the subjects of physics, math, chemistry, computer science, history, liberal studies, and honors. Dr. Ingham was instrumental in creating courses on the history of science taught in the history department and taught many other liberal studies courses, including freshman seminar, women in science, and seminars in nuclear war. Included in these files are syllabi, tests, lectures, notes, handouts, homework assignments, and course evaluations for various classes throughout his career at JMU. This series also contains handouts and lecture materials not associated with specific courses. This series is organized into two subseries –2.1. Courses and 2.2. General Teaching – which separates the material related to specific courses from miscellaneous teaching materials not necessarily associated with one particular course.
  - 2.1: Courses, 1960-2013
    - P100 Cosmology Lecture Fall 1980, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - P100 Exercises, ca. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Physics 100 Fall 1980-Fall 1988, 1980-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Phys 105 2006, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - P105E 11/08/07, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - P105 Fall 2008, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - P120 Lectures Fall 1991, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - P130 Final Exams, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Phys 130 Fall 1994, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Phys 130-135 Quizzes, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - P130-135 MC Use 1994-1998, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - P130 Fall 1995, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Phys 130, 1994-1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - P130 Hour Tests 1994-1997 (Folder 1 of 2), 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - P130 Hour Tests 1994-1997 (Folder 2 of 2), 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Phys 135 Spring 1995, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Phys 135 Exams 1995, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - P135 Summer 1995, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Phys 135 Exam, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Phys 135 Spring 1996 (MWF 3PM), 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Phys 135 Summer 1996, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - P135 Hour Tests 1995-1996, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Phys 140/150 (Folder 1 of 2), 1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Phys 140/150 (Folder 2 of 2), 1996, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - P140-150 Assigned HW, 1994-1998, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - P140-150 Ideas, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - P140 Samples and Practice, 1994-1997, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - P140 F196 Forms, 1996, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Phys 140, 1996-1997, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Phys 140, 1997, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Phys 140 (Folder 1 of 2), 1996-1998, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Phys 140 (Folder 2 of 2), 1996-1998, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - P150 Samples and Practice, 1994-1998, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - P150 Finals, 1995-1996, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - P150 Old HW Solutions, 1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Phys 150 Problems (Folder 1 of 2), 1994-1998, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Phys 150 Problems (Folder 2 of 2), 1994-1998, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Phys 215 1994, 1994-2000, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - P220 Fall 1985, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Phys 240 Lab Exercise Mass on a Spring (4180), 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - P240 Offerings: Sm 82, Sm 87, Fa 87, Sp 88, 1982-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Phys 240 Fall 1998, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - P240 Fall 1999 Old HW & Tests, 1983-1999, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Phys 240 Fall 1999, 1999, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - P240-001 Fall 2009, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Phys 240 Fall 2000, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - P250 Spring 2009, 2009, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Notes on Fluid Mechanics P245-260, 390 Ca. 10/82, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Physics 245 & 260 Exams 1981-86, 1981-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Physics 245 & 260 Fall 1982-86, 1981-1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - P245, Linearly Polarized Em Waves in a Vacuum: Summary, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - P245 & 260 Lecture Notes (Folder 1 or 2), 1983-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - P245 & 260 Lecture Notes (Folder 2 of 2), 1983-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - P245 & 260 Sample Homework Solutions (Folder 1 of 2), 1983-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - P245 & 260 Sample Homework Solutions (Folder 2 of 2), 1983-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Transparencies and Copies: Waves P245-260, 1983-1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - P245-260 Survey of E & M (Outline) Handouts Jan. 1985, 1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - P245-260 Transparencies & Copies: Thermo, 1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - P260 Final Exam Review (irreverent, insensitive), 1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Phys 260 Fall 2002 & 2003, 2002-2003, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Phys 260, 2002-2003, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Phys 260 PPS (Folder 1 of 2), 2002-2003, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Phys 260 PPS (Folder 2 of 2), 2002-2003, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Physics 260 Materials (Folder 1 of 2), 2003 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Physics 260 Materials (Folder 2 of 2), 2003 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Phys 260 Textbook & Topic Coverage, 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - P265- Spring 1999, 1998-1999, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Phys 265- Labs, 1999, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Phys 265, Life @ Low R# and Related Spring 1999, 1973-1999 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - P265 Homework Sets and Related (Folder 1 of 2), 1999-2002, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - P265 Homework Sets and Related (Folder 2 of 2), 1999-2002, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - P265 Hour Tests and Finals, 1999-2002, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Fluid Mechanics & Computational Fluid Dynamics & 265 (Folder 1 of 2), 1997-2001, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Fluid Mechanics & Computational Fluid Dynamics & 265 (Folder 2 of 2), 1997-2001, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Phys 265: Spring 2000 Intro to Fluid Mechanics, 2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Phys/Math 265- Spring 2001 MWF 2:30-3:20 Miller 109, 2000-2001, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Fluid Mechanics Film Notes, 1999-2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Phys 265- Spring 2002 (Folder 1 of 2), 2000-2002, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Phys 265- Spring 2002 (Folder 2 of 2), 2000-2002, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Phys 270, Modern Physic Handouts and Ref. Materials, 1968-1982, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Phys 270 Modern Physics, Notes & Exams, 1981-1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Phys 270: Spring 1998 Modern Physics, 1998-1999, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Phys 270 Spring 1998, 1993-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Phys 270, Training Spherical Coordinates, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - P270- Spring 1999, 1998-1999, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Phys 270, Modern Physics Biographical Sketches, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Phys 270 2000 (Folder 1 of 2), 1983-2002, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Phys 270 2000 (Folder 2 of 2), 1983-2002, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Phys 270 Sample Soln's, 2000, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Phys 270 '03 (Folder 1 of 2), 2002-2003, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Phys 270 '03 (Folder 2 of 2), 2002-2003, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Phys 270- Spring 2003 MWF 9:05-9:55 Tues 8:30-9:20 Miller 109, 2003, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Phys 270 Spring 2004 (Folder 1 of 2), 2003-2006, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Phys 270 Spring 2004 (Folder 2 of 2), 2003-2006, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Phys 270 Spring 2005 MWF 9:05-9:55 Tues 11-11:50 Miller 109, 2005, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Texts for Modern Physics, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Phys 280E MATlab Fall 2005, 2005, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Phys 285E 2006 (Folder 1 of 2), 1979-2007, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Phys 285E 2006 (Folder 2 of 2), 1979-2007, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Phys 285E (Maple) Spring 2007 Mondays 3:35-4:50 P&C 2378, 2006-2007, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Phys 285 2006, 2002-2006, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - P297 Relativity Homework Papers, 1993-2006 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - P297- Relativity Fall 2000 (Folder 1 of 2), 2000-2001, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - P297- Relativity Fall 2000 (Folder 2 of 2), 2000-2001, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - P297/M165, 2000-2001, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - P297-0301 MATLAB, 2001-2002, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Phys 297 Teaching Materials (Folder 1 of 2), 2000-2008, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Phys 297 Teaching Materials (Folder 2 of 2), 2000-2008, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Phys 297, 2001-2006, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Phys 297, 2006-2011, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Phys 297 MWF 1:25-2:15, 2008-2011, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - P297- Relativity, 2011, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Phys 297 Tests, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - P330 Physical Constants, 1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - P330 Formulas For Relativistic Mechanics, 1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - P330 Hour Tests & Finals, 1993-1994, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Phys 335, Fall 1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Homemade Xeroxes & Transparencies (Phys 330-335), 1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - P330-335 Lecture Notes, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Phys 335, Mod II F93: HW & Tests, Fall 1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Phys 335 The Stable Nuclides, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Phys 335 Homework, Spring 1982-1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - P335 HT's & Finals, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - P338, 1980-1983, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Physics 338 Hours Tests, 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Physics 338 Finals, 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Physics 338 Homework, Spring 1980-1981, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Physics 338: Lecture Notes, 1980-1981, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Phys 338, Nucl. Phys: Lecture Notes, 1974-1983, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Old P338 Computer Programs, 1983, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Phys 340 (Folder 1 of 2), 1999-2007, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Phys 340 (Folder 2 of 2), 1999-2007, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - P340 Mechanics, 2001, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Phys 340 Mechanics, 2004-2005, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - P340, Fall 2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Phys 340 (Folder 1 of 2), 2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Phys 340 (Folder 2 of 2), 2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Phys 341: Lecture Notes, Fall 1979, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Phys 341, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - P341 Central Force Motion, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - P341 Separation of Motions, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Phys 341 (Folder 1 of 2), 2003-2006, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Phys 341 (Folder 2 of 2), 2003-2006, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Phys 380, 2000-2004, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Phys 341, 2006, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Math/Phys 341, 2003-2013 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Math/Phys 341, 2013, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - P380 Homework, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Phys 390, 1978-1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Phys 390 Hour Tests & Finals, 1978-1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Phys 390 Notes, 1978-1981, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Phys 390, Drag-Coefficient Graphs Le Mahaute/Landan & Lifshitz, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - P390 Lecture Notes, 1985-1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - P390: Feynman II on a flow past a cylinder, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Lecture Notes in Phys 390 & Phys 580 Pt. 1, 1983-1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Lecture Notes in Phys 390 & Phys 580 Pt. 2, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - P390- Computer Applications, 2002, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Phys 390, 2002-2005, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Phys 390, 2005, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Phys 393 Research Projects, 2007, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - P397- Fall 2003 Enrichment, 2003, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Phys 397, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Phys 397 (Folder 1 of 2), 2008-2009, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Phys 397 (Folder 2 of 2), 2008-2009, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - P397A Chaos, 2001, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)